The Covenant has captured
a high-priority package.
Spartans, it's yourjob
to infiltrate enemy space and retrieve it.
Mission window: 10 minutes.
The target is equipped
with a location beacon...
...but you'll have to get close to read it.
It's a weak signal with a short radius.
A stellar magnetic field
is preventing the Covenant fleet...
...from making a Slipspace jump.
You'll be flying in
with EVA booster frames.
When you reach the Covenant fleet,
find the signal, find the ship...
...find a way in and grab that target.
The Covenant doesn't appear to realize
the full value of what they've acquired.
And that's the way we wanna keep it.
Complete the extraction
before they figure out what they've got.
All right, Spartans, you have your orders.
Good luck.
Yes, sir.
Captain.
What is it, Master Chief?
What happens if we run out of time?
Our only choice will be
to annihilate the Covenant fleet...
...the package and your entire team.
Is that clear enough?
I understand.
Spartan team,
the moment we break stealth...
...commence operation.
Five, four, three, two, one.
Disable cloak. Booster frame.
Launch.
Incoming. Optimize mobility.
Plasma rounds.
Scanning device is activated.
I've got a reading.
Are you sure?
No question.
Back me up, I'm going in.
Their shields are down.
The signal's coming from that cruiser.
Hang on, Solomon, wait for the Chief.
No time. I'll take my chances.
All right, if we're gonna do this,
let's make it fast.
Positive rwad
from the first scan. Something's off.
Hurry, Solomon.
Gotcha.
No.
- Kelly, it's a trap.
They took the bait.
Three have perished.
The rest are only a matter of time.
We must always show
our superior strength.
Anything less
and they will exploit our weakness.
Weakness. You have faced
these lowly creatures in battle...
...while your battalion perished.
That tells me only one thing.
You have not the heart
to die with honor.
Commander, two survivors detected.
Solomon.
Kelly, look.
I'm getting multiple readings.
They're decoys.
They know what we came for.
How do we find the real signal?
They've already told us.
What we want is in the heart
of this fleet.
The flagship.
Syrup formation, 2 o'clock.
Ignore them. Stay on target.
Four enemies approaching.
They know.
Will you run away once more?
They will be here. I shall face them.
You overestimate them.
They cannot touch this ship.
I pray that you are right.
Tight formation, now.
Concentrate Gauss cannons
on a single point.
Roger.
Shields at maximum charge.
They're still with us.
- I'm hit.
I'll hold them back.
I'm losing it.
Arthur!
You've gotta eject. I got your six.
You securw?
Give me the turrwt.
Now I got your six.
Let's get on with it.
Gauss cannon charge, 85 percent.
They're advancing position.
Ninety-one percent.
There it is.
Launch all missiles.
Gauss cannon, fire.
This thing's toast.
Then let them have it.
Looks like this is the right ship.
We got three minutes.
Let's sprint this.
Don't fall behind.
Copy that.
Go.
Three units passing Sector 25.
Stop them. Seal all hatches.
Frwd.
I got it.
The enemy is advancing.
- No.
Where is the major?
Go. I got this.
All right, the great journey ends here.
Fred.
Focus on the mission.
We get the target.
Commander, they're getting closer.
Getting closer, are they?
Not for long.
Chief.
Break off the entire block.
But, commander, our brothers have...
Silence.
Let them die with honor.
Chief.
Go get her.
Kelly.
Dr. Halsey.
John.
- It's you?
- Yes. I'm here to take you back.
- Sleep well, doctor?
No thanks to their driving, yes.
You seem to be in one piece.
Maybe your luck has rubbed off on me.
We make our own luck...
...but I'll always be there
when you need me.
Don't make a girl a promise
if you know you can't keep it.
- Still, thank you.
- Surw.
- Dr. Halsey...
It's not a proper rescue...
...until you get us out of here, right?
Agreed. We need to move fast.
John, wait.
We'rw out of time.
What? No.
We're clear
of the magnetic interference.
Stand by for Slipspace jump.
They're trapped in Delta section.
Separate the moment we jump.
But what of the major
and his group?
No matter.
He is already shamed.
His only path now is death or arbiter.
I had him.
Commander, you fool.
A thousand hells await you!
They're scuttling the ship.
And us with it.
But we make our own luck,
remember?
What are you suggesting?
What else? We improvise.
Doctor, we've got company.
Can't you do anything?
Can't this bucket go any faster?
What's happening?
Cutting it a little close, aren't we?
Fred.
Doctor, are you all right?
Yes, I'm fine.
These Covenant rigs fly like rocks.
It took us a bit to get rolling.
Incoming.
What?
Welcome back, Spartans.
You really are lucky. You know that.
Not lucky enough.
We lost two Spartans today.
Solomon and Arthur.
And that Elite we encountered,
he was strong.
I have to be stronger.
We all have to be stronger.
Something tells me
this is just the beginning.