In 2291, Slipspace technology
makes space colonization a reality.
In 30 years,
mankind establishes the Inner Colonies...
...in the heart of the Milky Way...
...and soon into the outer periphery.
In the year 2525, the human race
encounters an advanced alien alliance.
This alliance called itself the Covenant.
The Covenant decrees humanity
an affront to their gods...
...and the Human-Covenant War begins.
Within a decade, the Outer Colonies
are almost completely annihilated...
...by the power of the Covenant.
In the face of direct attacks on the
Inner Colonies by Covenant forces...
...humanity's only remaining hope...
...depends on a special unit
of genetically-augmented soldiers.
These soldiers were known
as the Spartan-lls.
They finally decide to give the order
to pull out and now this.
Damn it. It just ain't my day.
Mac, watch out!
Here they come.
Oh, damn it. This just ain't my day.
What the hell?
Maybe this is my day.
All right, men. Let's welcome
our chief petty officer with some backup.
And stay down.
How's Gamma-4?
Gamma-4 is gone.
Then that means this planet is finished.
And it won't be the last, sir.
I have the main unit on the line.
Rescue team will be in accordance...
...with the order to fully disengage.
Dispatching a rescue craft.
All active units respond immediately.
Team Gamma here, roger that.
We are completely surrounded.
Copy that, marine.
We're dispatching a rescue ship
to your location.
But I'm afraid we can't
exactly give you curbside service.
Sending coordinates for extraction point.
You're going to have to make your way...
- Wait a sec.
- What?
I know that voice. Is that you?
Daisy. That's you, isn't it?
Ralph.
Where do we go now?
I don't know.
- Anywhere but that place.
Yeah.
I don't wanna think about
what they'd do to us if we did go back.
We're not gonna be your toys anymore.
She's right. We're sick of your training.
We're leaving and you can't stop us.
What would our moms and dads
think of us if they saw us?
It's been seven years.
I wonder if they'd recognize us.
Not because we've grown up
but because of what's been done to us.
All of those years of training.
All those horrible surgeries
and the augmentations.
But everything's changed now.
And not just us.
You really think you can go home?
It doesn't matter. I'm going. I have to.
It's the only home that I have.
I guess tomorrow is goodbye then.
We won't be able
to see each other anymore, will we?
Of the five escapees from the facility...
...only subject Joseph-122
has been captured.
The search for the other four
is a Priority-Red directive.
Repeat. The search for the other four
Not again. I'm getting off this rock.
And I'm not going home
in a body bag either.
I'm gonna create a diversion. Keep low.
You make a run for the extraction point.
Jesus, they're everywhere.
All the more reason for us to move
as soon as we see the extraction craft.
That sounds like a good idea to me.
I'm gonna go find us a Hog.
Don't you dare slow down.
Heads up.
You okay down there?
They're here.
Notice any resemblance?
The secrecy of the Spartan-ll program
could not be jeopardized.
But the disappearance
of 75 recruits for the program...
...would've created difficult questions.
But if the children never vanished...
...there would be no questions to ask,
would there?
The clone lives a life in your place...
...the life that was originally meant
for you.
Come back to the facility, 23.
It is where you belong. It's home.
Sarge, are you all right?
I will be as soon as we're out of here.
Look, I'll cover you. Go on ahead.
There's no way I'm leaving...
Just go. Now.
Step on it.
Let's go.
Huh?
Faster, faster!
- Daisy!
- Chief!
I'm coming. Stay right there.
There's no time. Go, Ralph.
Get that ship out of here now.
Sometimes I have this drwam.
Always the same dream.
I dream I'm strong.
Stronger than anyone.
Like you. Just like you are.
Here. I want you to have this.
But why me?
I don't know, to be honest with you.
I just... Something tells me that I should.
I want you to take it.
My clone. He was... He was sick.
I think I killed him.
Don't do this to yourself, Ralph.
You did what you had to do.
So did I.
Daisy?
Transport to base.
Custody of Daisy-23
and Ralph-303 restored.
Subject's ETA, one hour.
After making contact with their clones...
...the remaining two escapees
used their small arms to commit suicide.
This is Charlie-1.
Sending new rendezvous coordinates.
Prepare to disengage.