You know this is a trap, do you not?
Coming was foolish.
Your words of dissent
are troubling to us.
We ask so little in return
for the gifts we offer.
Tell me, Arbiter,
is faith too much to ask in exchange?
Harka has chosen the path
of the Great Journey.
Why must you resist?
The Journey will take us farther
than this simple Covenant.
It will deliver us to godhood.
There is only one path for you.
Why must you deny the Journey
that we all must take?
The Journey is a lie!
Is it now?
You're dreaming, my love.
- What?
Forgive me, Han. I am distracted.
Can you not simply serve?
Perhaps, but only when you know
who you are actually serving.
Now I'm not so sure.
You uncertain?
Han, you should leave,
just for a little while.
I'll never leave you. I'm your wife.
And you are the general.
My place is at your side.
You are stubborn to a fault.
I could say the same of you.
Useless.
Focus. We are fighting Elite,
the right arm of the Covenant.
The gifts of the Forerunners are nothing if
you don't master the skills to wield them.
Master them you will,
for we are the men of Sanghelios.
Never forget that honor.
Sir! Yes, sir!
Walk with me a moment, Arbiter.
Roe.
I must ask you.
Ask your question.
Tell me, Arbiter, why do you insist
on provoking their patience?
They have given us formidable gifts.
Your status is at risk.
This heresy will strip you of your rank.
There is no rank without honor.
We were strong.
Sanghelios was strong
beforw this Covenant.
And we could be strong once more.
But we have strayed.
We live not for honor but for power.
Listen to yourself.
This talk is not just heresy,
it is treachery.
You are putting your bloodline at risk.
And what of your wife?
What of Han? Arbiter.
To protect the future of our clans,
please, please join.
Arbiter.
And now the game begins,
and I must play.
Thel.
I know they will come in force
to challenge me.
And I will not turn away from them.
I will answer their call.
It's not too late.
Cursed Arbiter. Cursed Arbiter.
Cursed Arbiter.
So honor is his strength.
Then we shall turn his precious honor
against him.
Draw him out and defeat him publicly.
The badge of Arbiter
will become a mark of shame.
Harka.
Persuade him, yes.
Take away what he finds so precious.
We'll show everyone
how high is the price of dissent.
Come in, Roe.
What's the matter?
Kill her.
Then he will have no choice
but to face me in battle.
I'm sorry.
We do this for the Great Journey.
He is a demon.
Han.
Han!
A shame that sword of yours
was too late to save Han.
Such a price for your honor, Arbiter.
You are not worthy
to speak her name.
But I promise
it is the last you will utter.
There will be time for talk
when I rule in your stead.
And declare your shame, Arbiter.