Hey, easy there, Berger.
What do you think you're doing?
- What?
- They're Helljumpers.
Every one of those guys
arw ODSTs from the 105th.
They're in a whole different league.
Let's go.
Unh. Aw, come on.
I wanna hear what they're saying.
No.
I don't get it.
How did everybody conveniently forget...
...that I'm the best shot
this side of Eridanus?
Getting assigned to backup
is a bunch of B.S.
Contingency. It's an important mission.
If the first sniper misses,
they take the shot.
I don't miss. I never miss.
This sucks and you know it.
I'm nobody's babysitter.
Especially not some
farm-boy moose hunter.
I hate to be the one
to break the bad news...
...but you weren't selected to be
the primary shooter on this mission.
So it seems
they want your farm boy to do it.
I guess that makes you the backup.
Sorry, O'Brian.
I'm the backup?
- And the shooter is a Spartan.
What?
And that means
this mission just got escalated.
This is Spartan Cal-141...
...who'll be the ranking officer
on this mission.
I realize that is highly unusual...
...and you have strong feelings
about Spartans.
You will keep those feelings
out of the mission and follow the plan.
Satellite rwcon shows radar
and magnetic signatures...
...on high end in the Arc star cluster.
These signatures indicate
a complex of buildings.
It's a logistical base.
The Prophet you are targeting
is in control of this entire sector.
Our mission is simple.
We want this Prophet dead.
We take out the Prophet, we will
stop the Covenant chain of supply.
If we achieve the goal of this mission...
...we will able to buy ourselves months
of tactical advantage.
And we will do all of this
with minimal risk to the UNSC.
Hmm.
Other than to this group, of course.
Cortez, fill them in on the details.
Right. You'll be flying into the atmosphere
with a Leonid-class meteor shower.
Meteor showers
are a regular occurrence on this planet...
...so that means entry and landing
should go unnoticed.
Calculations show reaching the target
will take a 14-hour fast march...
...from your entry point.
Once you reach the target...
...take out the Prophet
as soon as he steps off that ship.
Then you are to gather all data
relating to the unidentified alien ruins.
What do you mean,
they're not identified?
The architecture is
not Covenant-designed...
...and it sure as hell
wasn't built by humans.
They predate both sides.
This site is of the utmost importance.
We photograph everything.
That will be all, master sergeant.
Rejoin your men.
You will be dropping
in precisely five minutes.
With this mission,
there is no room for delay or error.
Good luck, and Godspeed.
Dutch, come in.
I'm all right. Where's O'Brian?
Over therw.
His oxygen tank.
Dutch, get the gear.
We gotta get him out of there.
Are you guys nuts? Why are you
throwing me around like that?
We lost Checkman in the atmosphere.
- What?
- And we almost lost you too.
Their logistics and
refueling base is here. We're here.
The Prophet will be coming in
at exactly 0800.
Hmm. Everything depends on us
getting a clear shot from this location...
...and we've got to hit him
as soon as he's exiting that ship.
It's two miles from the target...
...and should give us the elevation
for the shot.
It's pretty far...
...but it will give us enough cover
to make our extraction.
Assuming that the Spartan
can make the shot, that is.
And if we don't
make it to the target in time?
There won't be any second chances.
It's a long-ass march.
Then we better get marching.
Wanna take the lens cap off?
Knock it off, O'Brian.
I'm not crippled. Put me down.
You bitch any louder...
...and this place will be crawling
with Covenant.
Shut your mouth! He just got lucky.
That's twice.
Twice he had to save your dumb ass
already.
You could at least say "thank you. "
Man, those are some stairs.
The shuttle will be
touching down in two minutes.
After all this, he better
be everything they said he was.
Take him out!
Take the shot. O'Brian, now!
You're the only one who can do it.
It's the data on the ruins.
Tell them...
...to get it to Halsey.
She'll know.
No, you give it to her.
We both know
that's not gonna be possible.
Heard about what you guys did
down there.
Took out a Prophet...
...and stopped the Covenant's
supply chain dead for the sector.
They say a Spartan died there.
Went down faster than a new bood
on his first day.
I thought those guys
were supposed to be unbeatable.
Huh. I guess he didn't have what it takes
to hang with the Helljumpers, huh?
Shut up.
What's your problem?
What is the matter with you?
What'd I say?