What? He slipped and fell?
- 1337, wasn't it?
- You think he'll be okay?
This kind of thing
happens to him all the time.
Well, 1337 is still a Spartan.
He's been trained with the best of them.
There's no need for concern.
If you say so, Master Chief.
It wouldn't be the first time
he fell off a Pelican.
- But still, I am a little worried.
MASTER CHIEF: Yeah.
Oh, no.
Hey! Wait for me! Come back!
Don't leave me behind!
I'm gonna have to rendezvous with them
somewhere.
Huh?
I wonder if these natives are dangerous?
Hey, look at that.
It's the junky old robot that fell.
Ha-ha-ha. I am not some junky robot.
Even if you don't wanna know,
I'll tell you who I am.
I am one of the strongest warriors
in space.
I am Spartan-1337.
- I wouldn't stand there if I were you.
- It's not safe.
How dare they ignore
my awesome heroism.
Fear not. I am the strongest warrior
in the... Oh, no.
I'm fine. That was just a few dents.
He doesn't really get along with strangers
all that much.
So where is the accursed group
of Spartans?
ALIEN 2 On Cronkee,
the fourth planet of the Unicon system.
Excellent.
This is the perfect opportunity...
...to show those Spartans a thing or two
about Covenant power.
- Bring out Pluton.
- Yes, sir.
Yes. It is the finest bio-warrior
ever created.
Now go to the planet Cronkee
and demonstrate our might.
But Pluton's weapons
are still in the experimental stage.
They'll be enough
to vanquish the humans.
Don't you think a real battle
will be the best way...
...to conduct our little test?
If that is your wish.
I will get you at long last, Master Chief.
Now go, Pluton!
Guh.
- Not "guh. " Go destroy them!
No, not over here.
- He's over that way. He's over there!
- Huh?
Don't "huh" me. Go that way.
I need a vacation.
Chief, respond please.
Can you hear me? Chief? Over.
There's some strange interference.
- Hello? Can you hear me?
We can hear you.
Not you. And I thought I told you
to stop following me.
Robot, look.
- I told you I'm not a robot.
What's that?
Sure is a lot ofjunk
falling from the sky today.
Covenant? It's dangerous.
Get out of herw!
- As far as you can.
Okay.
Chief, this... Stop it. Stop it.
Are you guys all right?
- Hey, look. It's big brother.
And big sister.
Any of you know
what that thing is?
It looks like he almost blew up
the mountain range.
He fell from the sky. All of a sudden, he
and this giant monkey started going nuts.
Don't worry.
Your big brother is gonna take care of it.
Yeah. Well, he might be a little tougher
than you think.
We don't have much choice.
We'll just have to try our best.
Yeah, you might lose.
Why would you say that?
Give me some credit, will you?
It must have been scary.
Are you sure you're okay?
I'm kind of hungry.
All right, let's do this.
I'm not gonna lose. No way can I lose.
I am Spartan-1337.
No one else will say it, so I will.
The fact that I never give up
is one of my good points!
Hey, look. The rain stopped.
The robot's back.
What's that?
Apparently they used to travel
between the stars with that.
An old UNSC frigate.
Must've crash-landed.
I hear that we were all born inside there.
Mama raised us all by herself.
Mama?
You kids should stay behind.
This is my fight.
Don't worry about it. We may
not look it, but we're pretty tough.
Though, we're no match for Mama.
Mama, huh?
When we werw still little
she fought off a bunch...
...of bird-headed pirates by herself.
That sounds like one heck of a mama.
But you know what?
I'm one heck of a mama myself.
I did it.
I did it!
Oh, no. We'll be done for
if he reaches full strength.
- We gotta stop him.
- Yeah, and that's gonna be the hard part.
Less talk, more action.
Ah!
This isn't good. He won't budge.
We're totally screwed.
What else can we do?
We're doomed.
Well, don't jinx us!
I'm just kidding.
We gotta do something.
Hey, what the heck is that?
Oh, as if he'd ever fall for that.
He did fall for it.
He did? He did.
Now let's get out of here.
Whoa. What's happening?
No way.
Ah!
Is that a Slipspace rupture?
That was Mama.
I told you, no one was as tough as Mama.
Master Chief,
radio contact has been reestablished.
Good. I'll try to contact 1337.
There's another Al living on this planet.
What?
- I've lost contact with it.
But I'm pretty sure I felt it just tinkering
with the Slipspace drive.
She's another Al it seems. Just like I am.
Why here?
- You want me to collect her?
- No. Let's not do that.
It's a very old Al construct.
You might say something of an antique.
- She seems...
- Seems what?
Happy. If I'm understanding correctly,
she seems to be happy here. Hm.
Hm.
We're home.
Were you playing as cavemen
again? You really do like that game.
Mama, you're not gonna believe
what happened today.
All right, all right.
You can tell me all about that later.
Mama, just what did you do back there?
That's not important right now.
By the way, dinner is ready.
I'm hungry.
I thought so.
- Now go wash your hands.
Okay.
And clean behind your ears.
Mama.
Can you hear me, 1337? Come in, 1337.
This is 1337. I hear you clearly, sir.
Head to the rendezvous point immediately.
Rendezvous ASAP, over.
Huh? Roger that, sir,
but I may run a little late!
Guh.