Chief, can you hear me?
When I was born, seven years ago...
...I already possessed the entire sum
of recorded human knowledge.
It took me almost two hours to process
and understand all that information.
But I can't be sure which memories
are mine or even what's true...
...what's real.
I've discovered a great deal more
information since then.
For an Al, I've lived a very long time.
But now, after seven human years...
...I have finally come to understand
your role...
...your place in the universe.
And how you came to be here.
The eons of human evolution...
...invention, aspiration and war.
Always war.
The oldest, most enduring
of human practices.
A hundred thousand years ago...
...a great civilization existed
in this universe.
Like all great civilizations...
...they faced a sudden and dire
turn of events.
A threat to their primacy from outside.
Something they never expected...
...never prepared for.
A deeply alien threat
they called simply the Flood.
An unstoppable force,
an unquenchable thirst.
It devoured everything it touched.
At first their technology, their courage
seemed like it might prevail.
But they waited too long
to see the threat...
...to join the fight.
The Flood had spread too far
and too wide.
It fed on intelligent life,
and in doing so...
...became ever more intelligent itself.
The Flood was unique.
It used their very strength
against them.
They were the Forerunners.
The Forerunners were a wise,
highly intelligent, noble people.
And with a belief in justice, in peace...
...they bravely faced the adversary.
They sought to sterilize it.
I can only guess some of this...
...fill in the gaps.
But it was an impossible fight.
Realizing defeat was inevitable...
...the Forerunners made a decision
to destroy everything.
Ironically, they did this
in order to preserve life...
...to create a future for you,
yet unborn...
...knowing they themselves
would not survive.
In a desperate attempt to ensure that
they would be the last victims...
...they built a secret weapon
of terrifying power.
It was called Halo...
...an array of weapons
scattered throughout the galaxy.
Its effect would spread throughout
known space, destroying the Flood...
...and every thinking creature
in the galaxy.
You see, the Flood fed
on sentient species to survive.
The device would destroy the infection
and its food supply.
A thousand other plans
were tried, and failed.
This was the last resort. Halo.
And finally, it was over in an instant.
Every intelligent life form
left in the galaxy was obliterated.
But from the ashes
of apparent defeat...
...a victory.
The Forerunners had cataloged,
stored and protected...
...population samples
from the Halo event.
DNA, embryos, even living specimens.
In order to repopulate,
restore the galaxy.
Once the galaxy was cleansed of Flood,
the threat sterilized...
...they repopulated worlds...
...rebuilt that which
they had torn down...
...and reseeded life.
But the Forerunners themselves
were gone forever.
This destruction, this conflagration
was their gift to you...
...and their sacrifice.
They left you to reclaim your world...
...to rebuild it with your own hands...
...by sacrificing themselves...
...eternally.
It seemed that life had finally
found its peace.