Peace settled on the galaxy.
But it would be a fleeting peace.
For the great sacrifice was in vain.
The end of one war
did not signal an end to all wars.
It is a great irony
that the nature of war...
...always reveals the true nature
of those who fight.
And from their earliest days,
humanity began to fight...
...war after war.
It swarmed over the earth
and there was no ending in sight.
In the midst of the desire
to shed blood...
...you accidentally stumbled upon
the seeds of your salvation.
A great hope.
But you found something else, as well.
The seeds of your destruction.
There were many sacrifices.
Humankind was mired
in horrific conflict...
...meaningless bloodshed...
...leaving the great Earth
eternally scarred.
But finally...
...you looked up from the blood
and from the dirt and from the dying...
...to the stars.
You had not given up on the idea
of reaching out, yearning...
...seeking a new horizon...
...and finding a new space
to grow and prosper.
For the first time, all of humankind
was united in a shared vision...
...a common goal.
You realized that this once great planet
was now too small for you.
There were too many souls...
...and so little a world.
So you sought other worlds.
Worlds where you could escape
your addiction to destruction.
But the worlds you found
were never enough.
Never enough to satisfy
the age-old instincts.
Speed and distance did nothing
to separate you from your nature.
Old resentments,
ancient squabbles reemerged.
History began its terrible repetition...
...and once again, man fought man.
Like a virus,
war was always lurking inside you.
No matter how hard you tried to
suppress it...
...it just fought harder to get out.
It always got out.
Humankind had always looked to
the stars, to the heavens for answers.
Sometimes you didn't like
what you found there.
And while the galaxy revealed
few answers...
...it was more than willing to
confront you with new questions.
But there has always been one
truly unifying force in human history...
...one call that would always
unite you:
The emergence of a common enemy.
That enemy was the Covenant.
When this new foe emerged
and declared war against humanity...
...you finally united,
under a single banner.
And the weapons
you so carefully constructed...
...to control your own baser instincts
were now aimed not at yourselves...
...but against a deadly opponent...
...in pursuit of a shared goal:
The very survival of your species.
Then, as if awakened
by the arrival of the Covenant...
...a darker, far more ancient threat
emerged from its slumber.
Darkness born in eons past...
...became a threat to all life
once again.
And humankind and the Covenant...
...who had drowned for so long
in each other's blood...
...were united,
if only for the briefest moment...
...against a terrible enemy
they both shared.
Righteous souls continued to fight...
...believing that they could defeat
the darkness.
And as they fought together,
they stumbled together into peace.
This galaxy is vast.
Its wonders and beauty
are almost unfathomable.
But the galaxy also hides
dark secrets...
...some of which have lain dormant
since the beginning of time itself.
There is a danger in secrets...
...both in seeking and in knowing.
Some things are meant to be
hidden from view.
You see,
some mysteries defy understanding.
And sometimes even the things
we think we know are untrue.
Some secrwts should rwmain
untouched.
Secrets can tempt
your primal instinct...
...and lead you again into war.
The Halos were one such secret.
Chief, can you hear me?
I wonder why humans
must continue to fight.
I wonder if warriors
will ever disappear from this world.
Never.
There will always be warriors...
...and there will always be war.